<?xml version="1.0" encoding ="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE SCOPE_NOTE SYSTEM "scope_note.dtd">
<SCOPE_NOTE LNG="en" VERSION="4.5"><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1006</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Financing of temporary export deficits.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1015</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Indirect tax on the manufacture or sale of certain products.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1055</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The value that a business has over and above the stock in trade and the money invested in it.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1057</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The excess of current assets over current liabilities, representing the funds available for financing business activities.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1073</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Training paid for and given during active work periods.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1074</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Activities which aim at providing the skills, knowledge and aptitudes required for employment in a particular occupation (or a group of related occupations) in any field of economic activity.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1083</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Expenses incurred by a business other than direct manufacturing costs.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1087</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Territorial collectivities of the French Republic created in 1946 and replaced in 2003 by the Overseas Collectivities (COM).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1090</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>System whereby a company grants independent operators the right to market products or provide services using the franchiser's name and trademarks.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1091</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The non-collection of duties under the Common Customs Tariff in the case of goods imported for personal use or by private individuals.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1094</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Replaced the Latin American Free Trade Association (LAFTA) in 1981.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1095</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Reduction or minimisation of tax liability by unlawful means.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>110</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A large corporation or group of companies, built up through mergers and takeovers, which has interests in a wide range of business activities.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1105</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1130</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Arrangement insuring a creditor against default by a debtor.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1144</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Incentive to non-cultivation of land so as to limit agricultural production.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1147</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The chemistry of the earth's crust.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1149</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The study of the geographical distribution of economic resources and their use.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>115</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>For decision-making body in an EU institution or body, use  "decision-making body (EU)".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1150</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>For the influence of geography on the domestic and foreign policy of States, use geopolitics.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1152</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The study of the earth's physical properties and of the physical processes acting upon, above, and within the earth.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>118</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>In November 2001, the Council for Cultural Cooperation (CCC) was divided into four steering committees: the Steering Committee for Education (CDED), the Steering Committee for Higher Education and Research (CDESR), the Steering Committee for Culture (CDCULT) and the Steering Committee for Cultural Heritage (CDPAT).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1191</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1192</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Group capable of exercising pressure on a decision taken at government level.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1194</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The G-10 is a body within the International Monetary Fund (IMF) consisting of the Ministers of Finance and Central Bank Governors of the world’s most industrialised nations. It comprises the countries of the “Group of Seven” (US, Japan, Canada, France, Germany, Italy and the UK), plus Belgium, the Netherlands, Sweden and Switzerland.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1199</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A group of companies set up to obtain more favourable conditions from suppliers than would be possible if each acted individually.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>120</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A now obsolete organisation created on 14 June 1966 by the governments of Australia, Japan, South Korea, South Vietnam, the Republic of Korea, Malaysia, New Zealand and the Philippines. It was dissolved in 1975 as a result of disagreement among the members over the recognition of the People’s Republic of China.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1201</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Voluntary grouping of farmers involved in a particular type of production in the same area.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>122</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1247</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A company which exists for the primary or sole purpose of holding controlling interests in other companies.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1252</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Acknowledgement by an official authority of the quality of a product or service and of its conformity to standards.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1254</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Special Administrative Region of China since 1 July 1997.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1277</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for any aspect relating to methods and problems connected with animal nutrition. For the feedingstuffs themselves, use the specific term "animal feedingstuffs".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1283</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>European agreement relating to the work of vehicle crews involved in international transport by road.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>130</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1306</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The political, economic or cultural domination of one nation by another.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1308</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use only for the State which existed until 3 October 1990, the date of German unification.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1311</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Internal tax to which the staff of the European civil service are subject.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1318</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for the Federal Republic of Germany since the end of the Second World War and for the whole of Germany since reunification on 3 October 1990.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1326</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Tax owed by physical persons on their total income, calculated by adding earned income and investment income.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1330</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Paid by the employer as a proportion of the wages paid.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1334</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Disability due to an occupational accident or disease.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1336</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The holder of an elective office is forbidden to hold another office considered detrimental to the former.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1337</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Uniform trade terms formulated by the International Chamber of Commerce.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1342</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Grant for young farmers who are setting up a farm for the first time.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1351</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Measure of the extent to which a currency in the EMS deviates from its central rate against the ECU.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1354</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Instrument for measuring the movement of prices.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1433</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Fixed routes and facilities used in transport. Use in connection with the mode of transport concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>145</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Final consumption represents the value of the goods and services used for the direct satisfaction of human needs.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1460</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Should preferably be used in conjunction with the EU policy or sector concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1463</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>All procedures taken by two or more nations to create a common economic area.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1464</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for the various integration projects undertaken by the European States in the context of building a Europe of the Communities or together with other European organisations, such as the Council of Europe.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1489</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Outward investment in another country.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1492</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Inward investment from another country.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1517</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The political principle or practice of a country not to participate in international affairs.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1521</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Of land left unseeded after being ploughed and harrowed to regain fertility for a crop.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1549</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>In the context of a monetary penalty imposed by a Commission decision on an undertaking for a violation of EU competition rules, use "sanction (EU)".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1577</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Incorporation of substances into the soil to improve its physical and chemical properties.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1592</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for national laws, especially American and British. Do not use in the context of Community competition policy; use control of restrictive practices instead.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1599</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Period during which a legislative assembly exercises power.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>161</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Limit set on the quantity of goods which may be imported at a reduced or zero rate of duty.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1634</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A fundamental aspect of the free movement of persons within the European Union. This concept implies the abolition of discrimination based on nationality as regards employment, wages and other working conditions, as well as the right to social, economic and cultural integration of the migrant worker and his/her family in the host State. Not to be confused with labour mobility.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1658</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>166</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Contract between an employer and an individual employee.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1676</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Means of payment readily available without the need to move funds.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1679</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Register of persons who have the right to vote.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1682</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Repaying of a debt at a fixed rate or by annual instalments.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1689</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Closure of a factory by an employer in order to force workers to accept certain working conditions.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1699</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Law outlining general principles but allowing the government to use its parliamentary power to develop them further.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1716</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Special Administrative Region of China since 20 December 1999.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1728</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The branch of economics concerned with aggregates, such as national income, consumption, and investment.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>174</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Systematic evaluation of management methods by teams from either within or outside the organisation.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1746</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Obtaining more than half the votes cast.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1750</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>This requires more difficult conditions to be met than with an absolute majority, for example a two-thirds majority.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1759</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>If necessary, combine with the descriptors used for the affected organ or for the tropical or endemic nature of the disease.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1777</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The legal authority to act for another person in certain specified matters or the document conferring such authority.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1786</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use specific terms.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1788</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>If possible, combine the concept ‘agricultural market’ with the appropriate market sector(s)</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1789</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use to annotate resources covering agricultural markets in the EU. If possible, combine the concept ‘EU agricultural market’ with the appropriate market sector(s).</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1790</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Market in which goods are sold for immediate delivery.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1792</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Do not restrict usage to the EU.</SN><HN>In the EU context, the concept "common market" is now only used historically and has been replaced by single market.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1794</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1797</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Contract awarded at the discretion of an administrative body after a preliminary competition among potential contractors.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1799</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The place where national and foreign currencies are traded.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>18</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>If necessary, use in association with the area of activity concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>180</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Examination of industrial products at various stages of manufacture so as to ensure conformity to standards.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1804</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The place where transferable securities, mostly shares and bonds, are issued and traded.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1806</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use in association with country concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1809</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A market in short-term financial claims, e.g. bills of exchange, Treasury bills, interbank money and discount house deposits.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1810</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Contract binding a public body and a third party with a view to supplying work or services.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1816</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The band within which the value of a currency may fluctuate on either side of the central rate.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1825</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>All means of payment which can be used in a given country.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1844</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1847</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1860</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Intervention by a third party to resolve a conflict which could not be settled by normal administrative procedure.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1864</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A unit for the population census, every individual or group of individuals residing in the same dwelling.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>187</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1881</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Having an effect equivalent to that of customs duties or quantitative import restrictions.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1890</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Arrangement under which the landowner lets his land in return for part of the produce.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1892</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The study of the earth's atmosphere, especially of weather-forming processes and weather forecasting.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1901</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The branch of economics concerned with particular commodities, firms, or individuals and the economic relationships between them.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1903</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Refers to the part of Oceania situated in the North Pacific, comprising some 2000 islands. For the country, use the descriptor "Federated States of Micronesia".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1911</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Return of a migrant to his/her birthplace or last place of residence.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>194</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A written agreement on working conditions drawn up between one or more workers' organisations on the one side and one or more employers' organisations on the other.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1946</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Refers to the ability of individual workers to move around within the labour market. Not to be confused with free movement of workers.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1951</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The movement of an individual or group from one social class or status to another.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1970</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Currency which countries are willing to hold as part of their foreign-exchange reserves.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1988</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Charge on imports or exports of agricultural products introduced to offset the difference between actual exchange rates and "green" rates and thus prevent distortions of competition.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>1995</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Expression of disapproval or criticism addressed to the government by a parliamentary assembly.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2006</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Refers to industrial production in certain sectors where countries are jointly developing a programme of economic integration.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2011</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for any collective action promoting greater social justice.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2046</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Process in which representatives of employers and employees negotiate with a view to establishing a collective agreement.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2053</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The state of a nation which voluntarily refuses to become involved in an international conflict.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2062</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A level of subsistence or material welfare of a community, class, or person. Not to be confused with "Cost of living".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2070</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Defence pact between Australia, the United States and New Zealand.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2071</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Refusal by a nation to align itself to one or other of the major powers.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2072</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Parliamentarian who does not belong to any political group.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2079</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2082</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Standards concerning employment and working conditions, which are set out in collective agreements or laid down under labour law and labour regulations.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2099</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Obligation to provide financial support for a parent or relative.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>210</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for cooperation between European countries outside the EU context.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2102</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Organisation created in June 1996 in Antananarivo and dissolved on 25 March 1985. Its activities fall within the remit of the Organisation of African Unity (OAU), which became the African Union in 2002.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2106</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2116</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Replaced the Organisation of Central American States (OCAS) in 1991 and led to the creation of the Central American Common Market (CACM).</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2117</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2119</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2134</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Situation in which a market is effectively controlled by a limited number of sellers.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2135</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Situation in which a market is effectively controlled by a limited number of buyers.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2148</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2153</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Until 30.6.2009: Office for Official Publications of the European Communities.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>217</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Cooperation between the judicial bodies of different States, which may take the form of mutual assistance or the recognition and enforcement of judgments.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2173</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Combine with the relevant market sector(s).</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2183</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Treaty of military alliance signed in 1955 by the European Communist states under the influence of the Soviet Union. It was dissolved in 1991.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2189</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>For the names of international organisations refer to field 76.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2200</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2201</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Defensive alliance formed on 8 September 1954 between Australia, the United States, France, the United Kingdom, New Zealand, Pakistan, the Philippines and Thailand. It was dissolved in 1977.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2202</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Pan-African organisation which replaced the Organisation of African Unity (OAU) on 9 July 2002. It comprises all the countries in Africa including Western Sahara, apart from Morocco.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2223</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The voter makes up his own list by choosing candidates from several lists.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2235</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>An area of countryside for public use designated by a national government as being of notable scenic, environmental, scientific or historical importance.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2244</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use in association with country concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2280</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The gradual impoverishment of the population of a region or of a social class as the result of major changes in the economy of a region or country.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2284</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A period of long-term training substantially carried out within an undertaking and regulated by statutory law or custom according to a contract which imposes mutual obligations on the trainee and the employer.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2291</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Political representation comprising the countries of Eastern and Central Europe which were under Soviet domination from the end of the Second World War until the collapse of the Soviet communist system in 1989-1991.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2296</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>For names of countries and territories, see microthesaurus 7241 overseas countries and territories.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2298</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Member of an international organisation other than the European Union.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2319</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A systematic process of financial transfers directed towards the equalisation of the budget capacity or economic performance of different levels of federal governments.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2321</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Processing of imported goods on which no duty is paid provided the finished product is re-exported.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2322</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Temporary export of goods for further processing or repair under special customs arrangements.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2364</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which cover the entire range of products, otherwise use a more specific descriptor.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2371</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Dealing in commodities, currencies or securities in two or more markets so as to take advantage of any differences in the prices quoted.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2382</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A device which directly converts chemical energy into electric energy from a controlled oxidation reaction between an electrolyte and a fuel, usually hydrogen or hydrocarbon.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2392</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Plan for cooperative economic and social development in Asia and the Pacific.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2410</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>An area of land planted with crops, usually on a large scale.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2420</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Product used to alter the mechanical and thermal properties of certain solid substances in order to increase their flexibility, lower their breaking temperature and render them easier to shape.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2423</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Irregular submarine margin of a continent over which territory the coastal State has sovereign rights to extract resources.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2427</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Characteristic of a country or region where all job-seekers are provided with work.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2461</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Cost control: reducing public spending, controlling incomes and prices.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2462</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Intervention of the State in certain economic or social matters.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2526</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use in a general sense, not in relation to an identified noise source.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2529</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Marine pollution caused by waste from the land or from inland waterways.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2544</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The simultaneous growing of various crops in different areas of the same farm.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>255</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Created in 1952, this EU institution, which has its seat in Luxembourg, consists of three courts: the Court of Justice, the General Court (created in 1988) and the Civil Service Tribunal (created in 2004). The name "Court of Justice of the European Communities" was replaced by "Court of Justice of the European Union" when the Lisbon Treaty came into force on 1 December 2009.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2550</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>All persons already gainfully employed or who declare themselves to be seeking employment.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2552</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>All persons in active employment, discounting the unemployed.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>256</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Before 1.12.2009: ‘Court of Auditors of the European Communities’.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>258</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>As the principal judicial organ of the UN, the International Court of Justice settles, in accordance with international law, legal disputes between States which have been submitted by the States themselves and gives advisory opinions on legal questions referred to it by authorised United Nations organs and specialised agencies. Not to be confused with the International Criminal Tribunal for Rwanda, the International Criminal Tribunal for the former Yugoslavia or the International Criminal Court.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2588</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for State authorities or bodies and for local and regional authorities, taken as a whole.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2589</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Wrapping of a product, in the absence of the purchaser, in such a way that the amount of product has a fixed value in volume or mass which is chosen in advance.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2592</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The ECSC Treaty expired on 23 July 2002.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2626</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The principle by which costs of anti-pollution measures are chargeable to the party responsible for the pollution.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2639</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Prices fixed within the framework of the Common Agricultural Policy. For national prices, use prices of agricultural produce.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2641</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Includes, in addition to the price of the goods themselves, the cost of transport and insurance to the port of destination.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2652</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use in opposition to wholesale price, otherwise use consumer price.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2669</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>An enforceable decision made by an authority belonging to the administrative hierarchy.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2671</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The sales price of the goods and all expenses incurred up to the point of loading on board ship.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2675</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Price fixed by the State.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2686</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Price at sales point.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2699</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>In civil, commercial and social matters.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2718</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with products originating from fishing. Not to be confused with "fishery resources", which refers to existing resources.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2734</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which cover the entire range of products, otherwise use a more specific descriptor.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2735</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which cover the entire range of products, otherwise use a more specific descriptor.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2736</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which cover the entire range of products, otherwise use a more specific descriptor.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2737</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which cover the entire range of products, otherwise use a more specific descriptor.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>274</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The basic cost of the food, clothing, shelter, and fuel necessary to maintain life. Not to be confused with "Standard of living".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2761</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The total value of all goods and services produced domestically by a nation during a year. It is equivalent to gross national product minus net investment incomes from foreign nations.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2763</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which cover the entire range of products, otherwise use a more specific descriptor.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2764</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Foodstuff processed by quick freezing at minus 60 degrees followed by total dehydration.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2767</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which cover the entire range of products, otherwise use a more specific descriptor.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2768</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The total product of the various branches of the national economy over a fixed period, after deduction of capital consumption.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2769</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Total output of goods and services produced by a nation's economy before capital consumption.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2771</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Product produced in a given country; where more than one country is involved in the manufacture of a product, it is an originating product of the country where processing last took place.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>28</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A substance added to a product to improve its quality or increase its effectiveness.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2820</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Autonomous entity of the Kingdom of the Netherlands.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2829</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Founded in 1975 from the merger of the European Space Research Organisation (ESRO) and the European Launcher Development Organisation (ELDO).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2857</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The branch of psychology concerned with the working environment and personnel management.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2868</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The particular knowledge and skills required of a person in order to carry out his job.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2878</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Minimum number of participants that must be present at a meeting to make its transactions valid.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2880</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Minimum number of votes or proportion of the votes cast required to win a seat in a system of proportional representation.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>29</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Communication by means of press, radio, television etc.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2901</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The act by which a State confirms an agreement or treaty, thus internationally binding itself to such an agreement.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2904</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Training aimed at providing the skills, knowledge and aptitudes required for carrying out a task which is different from the previous one.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2906</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Arrangement under which an insurer passes on to other parties all or part of a risk he has assumed; this is not double insurance but a means of spreading large risks.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2922</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Research, the aim of which is to improve methods of production or to develop new products.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2926</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Document issued by an international organisation which does not imply any legal obligation. Use in association with the organisation concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2927</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use in association with the institution concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2929</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Body which supplements the social security scheme by giving its members additional benefits.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2938</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Substitution of one agricultural activity for another.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2939</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for a request to an administrative authority to cancel, change or withdraw a decision taken by the administration. Not to be confused with an action brought before an administrative court.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2941</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Action against the Council or the Commission for refraining to pronounce judgment in matters within their jurisdiction.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2942</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Action against States who do not respect the obligations imposed on them by the treaties.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2947</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The reprocessing of the waste materials originating during a production process to obtain similar or other products than the original material.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2959</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Operation in which a central bank discounts a bill presented by another bank which has already discounted it.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2964</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>An urgent court hearing to stop a situation which is against the law.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2966</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Vote by the general community to accept or reject a measure proposed by the government.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2967</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Preferential treatment given to goods produced in the European Community so as to encourage a Member State to buy from its partners rather than on the world market.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2970</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Reform covering all aspects of agrarian institutions, i.e. land reform, production structures, administration of rural areas etc.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2971</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Modernisation programme comprising a selective system of incentives for farms having an improvement plan.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2975</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Prices are no longer guaranteed if production exceeds a certain predetermined level.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2978</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Complete reform of the land system and conditions of agricultural production in order to eliminate obstacles to economic and social development.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2992</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Civil-law association formed for the purpose of preventing the break-up of private forestry holdings.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>2998</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The refusal of a producer or distributor to sell goods or services.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3007</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Company competing in the production of goods and services, the object of which activity is to maintain or create employment.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3012</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Media which derive part of their income from advertising.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3018</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Conference in which the speakers are situated in two or more places and connected with each other by facilities of telecommunications.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3021</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A special fee is required in order to receive programmes.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3036</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>One person legally holding several offices.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3038</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Decision of a body which is entrusted with a particular task to temporarily transfer the execution of this task to another body.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3044</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A direct vote by the qualified electors of a State regarding some important public issue.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3049</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The rights and immunities enjoyed by members of most legislative bodies, such as freedom of speech, freedom from arrest in civil cases during a session, etc.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3060</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Temporary grouping of independent businesses formed in order to carry out a financial or economic transaction. Not to be confused with a “joint venture”, an “economic interest grouping” or a “mixed-ownership company”.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3066</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Transformation or alteration in production rendered necessary by changes in economic conditions.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3083</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Supplies all data on aspects of agricultural activity, making comparisons possible and simplifying inclusion in economic statistics.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3087</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Introduced by the joint declaration of the European Parliament, the Council and the Commission, adopted on 4 March 1975, for the purpose of seeking agreement between Parliament and the Council. Use of this procedure was limited to "Community acts of general application which have appreciable financial implications, and of which the adoption is not required by virtue of acts already in existence".</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3099</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Act of general significance issued by an authority other than parliament.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3101</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Sum demanded not only for transport from one place to another but possibly also for certain additional services.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3102</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use in association with the institution concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3107</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use in association with the type of transport concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3167</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A duty imposed on imports of products so as to bring prices to a level equal to those on the domestic market.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3171</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Cancelled in 1987 and replaced by the Combined Nomenclature.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3189</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Form of international trade aimed at eliminating or reducing the transfer of currencies. Re-introduces bartering, counter-buying, and re-purchasing agreements.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3194</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Policy designed to give new impetus to economic activity which is in a state of decline or stagnation.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3196</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Organisation of international trade based on direct agreements between two states.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3204</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The various techniques used to render a product or a service as attractive as possible to the consumer.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3205</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The various measures taken to detect, forecast or stimulate the needs of consumers and subsequently adapt production and marketing.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3209</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Collective relations between employers and employees. For individual relations, use "personnel administration".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3212</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Distribution system in which retailers, while remaining independent businesses, join groups or associations which pool the purchasing of goods and provide affiliates with certain other services.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3217</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Centralised market which simplifies distribution channels by reducing the number of middlemen between producers and consumers.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3223</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Formely used for relations between the two blocs, this expression may still be used in the context of the new relations between the West and the countries of the former Eastern bloc.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3224</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Flow of goods and services between different industries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3234</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for relations between Member States. For relations between a Member State and the European Union, use "European Union membership".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3235</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Flow of liquid assets abroad.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3236</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Method used by companies to export capital by charging their subsidiaries greatly increased prices for products supplied by the parent company.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3238</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Historical concept valid before the introduction of the Euro.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3241</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Organisation of relations based on mechanisms which promote relations between each country and all its partners.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3244</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Joint coverage of a large risk by a number of insurers under a single contract, each insurer being liable for a portion of any claims.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3266</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Scale comprising of minimum and maximum limits within which prices can vary.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3269</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Tariff which favours national carriers (prohibited without the authorisation of the Commission).</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3272</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for national agricultural prices. Within the framework of the CAP use farm prices.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3290</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>To be applied to a branch of industry or at an inter-industrial level. Do not use for the internal reorganisation of a company.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3293</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Study of systems of communications and control in machines and living beings.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3307</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>When referring to the artificial reproduction of animals, use “artificial insemination”.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3308</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>When referring to the artificial insemination of humans, use “artificial reproduction”.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3312</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Power granted by law to a father and mother over the person or property of their child, who is not of full age and capacity.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3325</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Ability of an individual to change his/her position or rank within a profession or to change occupation.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>333</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Autonomous entity of the Kingdom of the Netherlands since 10.10.2010 (Netherlands Antilles dissolved).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3344</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Section of the budget concerned with social matters (pensions, health, education, family benefit etc.).</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3348</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Unlawful acts in general.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3381</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>British Crown dependency. Not part of the United Kingdom, but depends on it in matters concerning external relations. Not part of the European Union, but is associated with it through Protocol 3 to the United Kingdom’s Act of Accession.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3383</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Electoral system in which each party is represented in proportion to the numerical strength of the vote it receives.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3388</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use only for the region which existed until 1995, afterwards use descriptors "Ceuta" or "Melilla".</SN><HN>Ceuta and Melilla are autonomous cities since 13 March 1995.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3400</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Re-expansion of the economy after a period of recession.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3417</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for the requisitioning of staff in order to provide a minimum service in the event of disputes or strikes.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3443</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Amounts set aside by a business in anticipation of future liabilities.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3446</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Sum set aside in the accounts to provide for certain anticipated losses or expenditure.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3454</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>International control of the transfer and utilisation of nuclear weapons.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3457</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A protected area of importance for wildlife, flora, fauna or features of geological, biological or aesthetic interest, which is reserved and managed for the conservation and restoration of the natural environment.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3461</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use in connection with the countries concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3462</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Agreement between two states which is only legally binding for these two states with the benefits typically not shared with other (third) countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3466</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Formality which acknowledges agreement on the text of a treaty but which does not normally bind the State.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3467</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Includes treaties, codes of conduct, resolutions, plans of action and declarations of inter-governmental organisations. Use in association with organisation concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3470</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Document issued by an international organisation, the legal implication of which may vary. Use in association with the organisation concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3472</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>To combine with the subjects of the convention. 
Complete list of the Council of Europe's treaties 
available at: http://www.coe.int/en/web/conventions/full-list (Accessed 14 June 2016)</SN><SN>The Council of Europe Treaty Series groups together all
 the conventions concluded within the Organisation 
since 1949. Whatever they are called ("agreement",
 "convention", "arrangement", "charter", "code", etc.), all
 these texts are international treaties in the sense of 
the Convention of Vienna of 1969 on the law of treaties.
Source: COE. Available at: http://www.coe.int/en/web/conventions/about-treaties (Accessed: 14 June 2016).</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3476</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use in association with country concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3479</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Political and economic relations between East and West Germany.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3482</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A text which is binding on States or private persons and lays down international standards simplifying the drafting and application of national policies, laws and regulations in specific fields.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3483</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Measures taken against a State which has violated international law.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>349</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use in connection with the institution concerned.</SN><HN>With the entry into force of the Treaty of Lisbon (1.12.2009), decisions no longer need necessarily to be specifically addressed. They have therefore acquired a wider scope and have replaced, in particular, all the instruments formerly used for the CFSP.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3491</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Cooperation between States aimed at drafting joint regulations or harmonising legislation.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3503</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>International obligation to repair damages caused to foreigners as a result of acts contrary to international law.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3510</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Area free from nuclear arms or foreign military installations.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3516</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Return to the job market after a long period of absence due to maternity leave, children's education, military service, imprisonment, etc.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3520</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>System in which an employee agrees to work fewer hours, resulting in a reduction of salary, in order to permit an unemployed person to work.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3521</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Person connected to a State either by nationality or sovereignty. If necessary, use in association with the State concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3527</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Work which requires the recruitment of a person for a fixed length of time.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3532</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Training provided for those workers no longer familiar with technical progress in order to update their skills.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3540</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Term solely concerning workers posted abroad in accordance with company policy. Not to be confused with migrant worker.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3542</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>One who organises, owns and manages a business, assuming the risks involved.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3552</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Work carried out at a distance using telecommunication services or computers.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3568</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Subsidy, under the common agricultural policy, on exports of agricultural produce to provide producers with guaranteed prices.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3574</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Associations of certain professions which are not included in the trade union movement.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3575</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>An association of employees, usually not limited to a single company, formed to protect or improve incomes and working conditions by collective bargaining with employers or employer organisations.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>361</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>System in which the administration of a region is executed by local authorities subject to a central authority.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3614</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Act of passing through a country when the points of arrival and departure are situated outside this country.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3627</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Incorporates research activites, centres of higher education and advanced industries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>364</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Enforceable decision taken by a legislative body.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3659</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for income of individuals or undertakings, otherwise use national income.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3666</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>With the entry into force of Regulation EU 2015/2424 amending the Community trade mark regulation on 23 March, OHIM became the European Union Intellectual Property Office (EUIPO), and the Community trade mark became the European Union trade mark.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3675</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Group of States which, after taking part in the 1967 Algiers Conference to prepare the Unctad assembly, compiled a list of requirements of underdeveloped countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3676</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The Contadora Group was created in 1983 by the Foreign Ministers of Mexico, Venezuela, Colombia and Panama, and was incorporated into the Rio Group in 1987. Use “Rio Group”.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3686</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The aggregate earnings of labour and property which arise from the current production of goods and services by the nation's economy.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3700</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>European agreement relating to the international transportation of dangerous goods by inland shipping.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3708</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Secretariat of the International Labour Organisation (ILO).</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3722</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Superseded the WAEC (West African Economic Community) and the WAMU (West African Monetary Union) in 1995. The name WAEC was adopted in 1970 following the reorganisation of the CUWAS (Customs Union of West African States), which was created in 1959.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3786</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The total construction work involved in setting up a hydroelectric plant.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3796</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Branch of industry using biotechnology at an industrial and commercial level.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3797</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Branch of technology aimed at cultivating micro-organisms, animal and vegetable cells and their components.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3854</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A person who works for a public or private employer and receives wages, salaries, room and board or other compensation for his efforts. Use in the case of professions, otherwise in a more general context use the descriptor "labour force".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3915</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Every person has the right to participate in economic, social, cultural and political development, and to contribute to it and benefit from it. Human rights and basic freedoms are an integral part of such development.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3919</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Various measures whose purpose is to improve conditions for children in society.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3938</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Right attached to one piece of land entitling the owner thereof to some right over adjacent land but not to take any part or produce thereof.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>3969</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Assistance granted to persons in need to enable them to exercise their legal rights.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4009</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Effects of international law, particularly of treaties, on the national law of a State.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4012</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The law applied to economic cases brought by public persons.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4013</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Sector of the economy regarding intellectual services, education, consultancy, information, research.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4014</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>As of the entry into force of the Lisbon Treaty (01.12.2009), use "decision (EU)".</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4015</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use in association with the institution concerned.</SN><HN>With effect from the entry into force of the Treaty of Lisbon (1.12.2009), use "directive (EU)".</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4020</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>As of the entry into force of the Lisbon Treaty (1.12.2009), use "recommendation (EU)".</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4022</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>As of the entry into force of the Lisbon Treaty (1.12.2009), use "regulation (EU)".</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4029</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A work contract which guarantees a long period of employment.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4035</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>As of the entry into force of the Lisbon Treaty (1.12.2009), use "Accession Treaty (EU)".</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4040</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use in association with the type of relation or agreement concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4046</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Association which was disbanded on 31 December 1998.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4054</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>New designation for the European System for the International Clearing of Vacancies and Applications for Employment, brought in as part of the renewal process and approved by the Council in 1993.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4056</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Set up under the Treaty of Rome to improve employment chances for workers in the internal market and contribute to the raising of living standards.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4060</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Objective of a reform project of the treaties for the creation of a European Union.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4063</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with the advantages or disadvantages of membership of the European Union.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4065</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Since the Lisbon Treaty came into force (1.12.2009), common positions concerning the area of freedom, security and justice and the common foreign and security policy have been replaced by Council decisions. Use "decision (EU)".</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4066</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Since the Lisbon Treaty came into force (1.12.2009), "joint actions" concerning the CFSP have been replaced by Council decisions. Use ""decision (EU)".</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4069</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4070</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Project launched in the 1970s to coordinate Member States’ foreign policies. EPC is incorporated into the Treaty on European Union and enshrined in the “common foreign and security policy”. Use “CFSP”.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4074</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with the management of financial risks or business risks.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4076</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Potential and more-or-less predictable danger which can arise at an industrial site, with immediate serious consequences for the adjacent population, property or environment.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4080</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>These come from the application of the common customs tariff to imports from third countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4111</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Deliberate production of new genes by substituting or adding a new genetic component.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4119</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Official publication of a new law, thereby putting it into effect.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4130</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Clause appearing in certain bilateral agreements whereby the contracting States agree to extend to their reciprocal trade the customs advantages which they would grant to another party.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4132</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Budgets annexed to the general budget for certain public bodies (e.g. Post Office) which are not independent legal entities but have a degree of financial autonomy.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4136</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for the body providing a service. Not to be confused with the descriptor "services of general interest".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4175</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with “head of State”.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>419</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Refusal to obey laws considered as unjust by means of non-violent protest.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4192</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Partnership established for the exercise of certain liberal professions.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4194</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Company owned partly by the government or a public body and partly by private-sector investors.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4198</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A type of society where growth in production results in a proliferation of consumer goods and consequently in the creation of new needs and desires.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4201</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Unregistered company without corporate or legal personality which is not required to make itself public and which may remain secret.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4213</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Study of a sample representative of a population so as to determine characteristics.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4216</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The right of a nation or people to determine its own form of government without influence from outside.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>423</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Public or private debt to foreign creditors.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4237</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Short-term Community financing intended to meet financial requirements resulting from a temporary deficit in the balance of payments.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>424</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Liabilities of central government and other public bodies to individual creditors.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4241</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Principle under which appropriations must be used for the specific purpose laid down in the budget.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4247</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>System of loans or gifts made to ACP States in order to remove the effects of market fluctuation and production risks upon agricultural export receipts.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4250</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Return to a state of economic stability after a period of fluctuation.This can apply to one market or the entire economy.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4254</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Stage of no growth.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4275</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Concerns countries or regions whose status is controversial.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>428</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Created in 1958 as the European Nuclear Energy Agency, the organisation was officially renamed the Nuclear Energy Agency in 1972 in order to reflect its international status.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4286</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Lowest level which stocks of any item should be allowed to reach in the course of normal business.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4290</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Stocks of commodities held to reduce fluctuations in world commodity prices.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4304</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use also for EU bodies.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4321</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Votes validly cast excluding blank and invalid ballot papers.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>435098</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>For documents relating to human therapeutic cloning, combine "human cloning" with "stem cell".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4352</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The branch of forestry that is concerned with the cultivation of trees.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>435265</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>For the geographical distribution of political processes, use political geography.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4360</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>System in which defined data are collected, processed and communicated to assist those responsible for the use of resources.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4370</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Replaced by ERM II (exchange rate mechanism II) at the start of Stage Three of economic and monetary union (EMU) on 1 January 1999 when the single currency was launched.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>437422</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>It replaced the MEDA and Tacis programmes on 1 January 2007.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4379</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Transport price fixed in advance according to a systematic table.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>438855</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Term introduced by the Lisbon Treaty (1.12.2009).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4389</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Relationship between the production and consumption of a product within a given area.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4395</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Special rate for conversion between the ECU and a national currency for the purposes of farm prices, deviating from the normal exchange rate.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>439592</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The function of President of the European Council was instituted by the Lisbon Treaty (which came into force on 1.12.2009).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4401</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Tax on legal documents etc., the payment of which is certified by the attaching or impressing of official stamps.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>440238</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Legislative procedure replacing the codecision procedure with effect from the entry into force of the Treaty of Lisbon (1.12.2009).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>440265</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Term introduced by the Lisbon Treaty (1.12.2009).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4403</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Having an effect equivalent to that of customs duties.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>440605</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Term introduced by the Lisbon Treaty (1.12.2009).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>440631</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Term introduced by the Lisbon Treaty (1.12.2009).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>440657</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Term introduced by the Lisbon Treaty (1.12.2009).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>440710</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Term introduced by the Lisbon Treaty (1.12.2009).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>441001</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>To be used together with the agency's field of competence.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4411</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use only for the State which existed until 1 January 1993, on which date the Czech and Slovak Republics separated.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4415</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use specific terms.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4416</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Operations, equipment and measures involved in the processing of food.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4421</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Technology which can improve the productivity of traditional methods without requiring the capital or educational training necessary for advanced technology.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4424</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The transmission, broadcasting or reception of signals, sounds, messages or information of any nature by electric means, e.g. wire, radio or other electromagnetic systems.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4426</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>All techniques used to determine the physical and biological features of objects by measures carried out at a distance without material contact with the object concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4428</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>System using a network of cables to broadcast audio or visual programmes to a large number of users.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4430</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>All services, other than the normal telephonic and telegraphic services, which use teleinformatic techniques and which can be received by users of a telecommunications network.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>443137</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>New title of the "Treaty establishing the European Community" (originally "Treaty establishing the European Economic Community") following the entry into force of the Lisbon Treaty.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4437</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Succeeded the European Payments Union and provided the institutional framework for monetary cooperation between the countries of the Organisation for European Economic Cooperation (OEEC) from 1958 to 1972.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4440</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A measure of a country's trading prospects based on the ratio of an index of export prices to an index of import prices.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>445178</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Term introduced by the Lisbon Treaty (1.12.2009).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>445259</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Term introduced by the Lisbon Treaty (1.12.2009).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4457</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>With effect from the entry into force of the Treaty of Lisbon (1.12.2009), use "(EU) opinion".</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4460</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Western part of the island of Timor which has been part of Indonesia since 1945.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4461</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Eastern part of the island of Timor which proclaimed itself independent on 20 May 2002 after being occupied by Indonesia since 1975.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4479</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use the specific terms.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>448</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Order from a Head of State or Government.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4480</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The ECSC Treaty expired in July 2002.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4481</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Original name of the founding Treaty, as signed in Rome in 1957.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4483</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN><HN>Military alliance (1955-1991) which was composed of the Soviet Union, Albania (until 1968), the German Democratic Republic, Bulgaria, Hungary, Poland, Romania and Czechoslovakia.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>449</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use in association with the institution concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4496</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The transfer from one country to another of the knowledge, manufacturing techniques and equipment necessary for the production of goods.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4499</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Customs transit procedure which applies within the European Union.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>450</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for the respect of voting instructions given to parliamentarians by their party or parliamentary group.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4500</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Arrangements for moving goods through a territory without payment of customs duties.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4506</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The dispatch of goods using several means of transport, the greatest distance possible being covered by rail, inland waterway or sea, and the shortest by road.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>450652</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>On 1 January 2007, this fund replaced the Guarantee Section of the European Agricultural Guidance and Guarantee Fund (EAGGF).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>450658</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>On 1 January 2007, this fund replaced the Guidance Section of the European Agricultural Guidance and Guarantee Fund (EAGGF).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>450953</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Established in July 2008 following the merger of the African Court of Justice and the African Court on Human and Peoples' Rights.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4518</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Transport movement where the points of arrival and departure are situated within the territory of the same State.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>451885</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Autonomous entity of the Kingdom of the Netherlands since 10.10.2010 (Netherlands Antilles dissolved).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>451912</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Since the dissolution of the Netherlands Antilles on 10.10.2010, Bonaire, Saint Eustatius and Saba have gained the status of autonomous special municipalities of the Netherlands.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>451941</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>British Crown dependency. Not part of the United Kingdom, but depends on it in matters concerning external relations. Not part of the European Union, but is associated with it through Protocol 3 to the United Kingdom’s Act of Accession.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>451991</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>British Crown dependency. Not part of the United Kingdom, but depends on it in matters concerning external relations. Not part of the European Union, but is associated with it through Protocol 3 to the United Kingdom’s Act of Accession.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>452085</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Replaced the "Financial Instrument for Fisheries Guidance" (FIFG) in 2007 and is followed by the "European Maritime and Fisheries Funds" (EMFF) for the period 2014 – 2020.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4524</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Agreement concerning the international textile trade.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4536</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Permission to cross customs territory or to convey imports to a customs warehouse or customs clearing centre without fulfilling customs formalities at the border.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4543</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Only to be used for documents of a very general nature, otherwise choose a more specific descriptor.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4548</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Employment with monthly working hours which are shorter than those normally worked by full-time employees.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4549</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The holding of an employment over and above the basic job, usually in breach of rules laid down by law.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4556</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Worker who carries out a remunerated activity in violation of the law.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4586</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The Central African Economic and Monetary Community (CAEMC) was established in 1994 and encompasses the activities of the Central African Monetary Union (CAMU) and the Central African Customs and Economic Union (CACEU). It comprises Cameroon, the Central African Republic, Congo, Gabon, Equatorial Guinea and Chad, and its defining feature is that its members recognise the same unit of currency (the CFA franc).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4587</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4590</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4600</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>States which have established among themselves a single customs area with common external customs regulations and tariffs.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4603</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Created in 1950 by 18 member countries of the Organisation for European Economic Cooperation (OEEC), it was dissolved in 1958 and replaced by the European Monetary Agreement.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4607</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4610</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Intergovernmental programme for cooperation in the field of scientific and technological information.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4618</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for the growth of cities, both in number of inhabitants and in territorial extent, and for the consequences of this growth on the way of life.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4619</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Science and policies concerning the construction and organisation of towns.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4620</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use only for the State which existed until the break-up of the Soviet Union.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4642</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Total value at current market prices of all the issued shares of a company or of the shares of all the companies listed on a market.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4690</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4698</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Videography where messages are broadcast by a television network.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4699</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Videography where a telecommunications network transmits the requests of users and the messages received in reply.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4712</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Town which is politically and economically dependent on another town.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>473</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Extraction of alcohol.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4748</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>If necessary, use in association with imports or exports.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4753</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Procedure in France whereby the government can force the Assembly to vote on the whole text under discussion, allowing only those amendments proposed or accepted by itself.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4764</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Form of voting in which candidates are numbered in order of preference by the voter.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4771</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Dissemination to farmers of technical, financial and economic knowledge.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4789</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>States which have eliminated customs duties among themselves and established on their territories an area within which goods move freely.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4790</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Combined with the the sub-area or division listed under the FAO Fishing Areas. Source: FAO (Food and Agriculture Organization of the United Nations). Available at: http://www.fao.org/fishery/area/search/en (Accessed: 26 October 2015)</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4793</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Section of territory where customs duties are not applicable.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4805</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Geographical area inside of which there is a uniform transport price.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4811</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Body established with a view to acquiring land or farms for sale which are intended to be re-assigned after possible development.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4828</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Agreement under which the main exporting countries and the main importers of a commodity undertake to respect a regulation relating to the international trade in this product.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4845</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4851</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>General demand for labour or demand in particular industries, sectors or economies.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4887</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use the descriptor "humanisation of work" for questions concerning the quality of life at work.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4890</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Direct or indirect transformation of solar energy by living beings.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4892</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>All forms of energy originating from the transformation of biomasses.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4900</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Gaseous substance resulting from the decomposition of organic matter.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4930</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>All organic matter which forms living beings, animal or vegetable.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>4959</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with two-party system.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5017</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which cover the entire range of products, otherwise use a more specific descriptor.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5021</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>An exchequer bill payable at short notice.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5033</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Market where the bulk sale and purchase of commodities (wool, coffee, cocoa) take place, often for future delivery.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5048</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for noise pollution from a known source, such as a vehicle, a machine, a discotheque,a motorway or an airport.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5051</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Term used until the Lisbon Treaty came into force (1.12.2009).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5057</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Budget for ECSC activities, separate from the general budget of the European Communities.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5062</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Incorporation into the budget of particular items of revenue and expenditure.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5070</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>When referring to customs, use "customs formalities".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5074</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Group of leaders of the Opposition, each assigned to watch a major government department so as to challenge government policy in that field. If government changes, members may be appointed to those departments they have shadowed.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5083</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5086</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Intergovernmental economic organization (1949-91) founded by USSR, Bulgaria, Czechoslovakia, Hungary, Poland and Romania. In the course of time Albania (1949-87), GDR (1950-90), Mongolia (1962), Cuba (1972) and Vietnam (1978) took also part as well as Yugoslavia (1964) as associate member.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5087</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Intergovernmental economic organization (1949-91) founded by USSR, Bulgaria, Czechoslovakia, Hungary, Poland and Romania. In the course of time Albania (1949-87), GDR (1950-90), Mongolia (1962), Cuba (1972) and Vietnam (1978) took also part as well as Yugoslavia (1964) as associate member.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5096</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Annual reference period for the fixing of farm prices.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5107</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Regional cooperation organisation comprising Kenya, Uganda and Tanzania.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5131</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Procedure established by the Single European Act (1986) and replaced by the approval procedure when the Lisbon Treaty came into force (on 1.12.2009).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5138</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Financial instruments used by the European Commission to promote the economic and social cohesion of the European Union.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5143</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Strip of water extending beyond the territorial waters at a distance of less than 24 miles from the coast.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5146</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use to describe the state of the economy of a country, a group of countries or a region at a specific time.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5152</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Transport potential of an undertaking.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5169</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Ethical aspects of techniques involving human intervention in biological processes.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5177</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Information network on education in Europe.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5180</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Text transmission service enabling the various functions of text processing to be carried out remotely.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>519</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Countervailing duty imposed on imports to discourage dumping.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>520</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Every person has the right to work and to exercise a profession freely chosen or accepted.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5258</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>With the entry into force of the Treaty of Lisbon on 1 December 2009, the names "European Union" or "EU" have replaced "European Community", "Community" or "EC".</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5265</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5267</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Association of independent companies with similar activities, formed for the purpose of limiting or eliminating competition in a particular market.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5270</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A company's gross cash flow is its net profit before charging depreciation. The net cash flow consists of retained profits plus depreciation.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5276</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Sum which a candidate has to deposit at an election.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5282</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>In accordance with the Cotonou Agreement, the resources and activities of the Centre for the Development of Industry (CDI) were transferred to the Centre for the Development of Enterprise (CDE) in August 2000.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5283</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5291</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>To be used for social aspects of death and attitudes towards death.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5302</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5306</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The field of medicine in which radio nuclides are used for diagnosis or therapy.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5312</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>May be linked to the subject area concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5313</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>To be used for a country or within an institution.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5325</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Any substance used for the abnormal enhancement of an individual's physical or mental performance.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5328</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>New name of the Court of First Instance since the Lisbon Treaty came into force (1.12.2009).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5334</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>To be used for the transfer of information in a legal or ethical context.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5346</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A chemical compound occurring naturally in fibrous products such as cotton and kapok, and used in the manufacture of paper, rayon, cellophane, etc.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5385</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Method of adding sugar to wine.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5393</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Drafted in 1948 in order to establish an International Trade Organisation but failed to enter into force.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5395</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The European Social Charter, which guarantees social and economic human rights, was adopted by the Council of Europe in 1961. The 1996 revision came in to force in 1999.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5407</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use with "association agreement (EU)", "trade agreement (EU)" or "cooperation agreement (EU)".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5409</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Agreements concluded jointly by the Member States and the European Communities in areas of shared responsibility.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5412</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Action brought by a victim of crime in association with criminal proceedings.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5416</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with action to establish liability on the part of an administration.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5417</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Action brought before a criminal court by the public prosecutor's department with a view to passing an appropriate sentence on the perpetrator of a crime.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5419</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Comprises the annual technical adjustments made by the Commission and the adjustments connected to the implementing conditions.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5420</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Act by which a State or international organisation declares its readiness to be bound by an agreement already concluded by other parties.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5437</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>544</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>System of fisheries management under which access to fishing grounds is governed by participatory rights that comprise not only the entitlement to catch fish but also specifications regarding the following aspects: how fishing may be conducted (e.g. type of vessel and engine), when and where it may be carried out and the size of authorised catches.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5449</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for the parliamentary body of an international organisation.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5450</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for institutions.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5463</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Biological diversity within and across species, and within terrestrial or aquatic ecosystems.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5464</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A biotope is a homogeneous area of similar ecology which constitutes the habitat of a specific animal and vegetable community.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5465</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for assets derived from an illicit activity, such as drug trafficking.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5471</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Commercial flights operated between two places in one country by another country's airline.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5478</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Superseded the NACC (North Atlantic Cooperation Council) in 1997. It brings together the member countries and partner countries of NATO, allowing them to discuss and confer on political and security matters.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5480</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A group of workers, performing similar work and trained to identify and solve problems, who volunteer to make recommendations relating to the improvement of productivity, quality, work morale, etc. in an undertaking.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5494</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Clause allowing a Member State to refrain from or to delay the application of certain provisions of an agreement.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5495</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The Wassenaar Arrangement on Multilateral Export Controls for Conventional Arms and Dual-Use Goods and Technologies superseded the COCOM (Coordinating Committee for Multilateral Export Controls) in 1996.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5499</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The pursuit of balanced and sustainable development throughout the European Union.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5501</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Constitutes a local territorial area. Not to be confused with the descriptor "local government".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5506</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The "Comitology" Decision was repealed and replaced on 1 March 2011 by the "Comitology" Regulation.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5507</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The "Comitology" Decision was repealed and replaced on 1 March 2011 by the "Comitology" Regulation.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5511</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>On 1 March 2011, this Regulation repealed and replaced "Comitology" Decision 1999/468/EC and introduced two new procedures: an advisory procedure and an examination procedure. These procedures thus replace the advisory procedure, the management procedure and the regulatory procedure introduced by the Decision adopted in 1999.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5512</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for the legal or illegal trade in any part of the human body or any product derived therefrom.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5519</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Where appropriate, use in conjunction with the EU institution concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5526</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>ILO governing body, made up of national delegations representing government, workers and employers.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5529</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Leave granted to take part in a political campaign or to carry out the duties of an elected representative.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5539</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>This is the fourth resource, introduced in 1988, and is based on GNP and the application of a rate, set under the budget procedure, to the total GNP of all the Member States.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5540</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use only for the control of persons and their luggage when crossing a frontier.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5544</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Historical concept referring to cooperation in the field of justice and home affairs, which was subsequently incorporated into the Schengen Agreement and then into the institutional framework of the European Union. Use “
AFSJ” (area of freedom, security and justice).</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5546</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Cooperation in the field of environmental protection.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5585</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Development which allows present needs to be satisfied without compromising the capacity of future generations to satisfy their needs too.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5598</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for matters relating to the legal bond between two or more persons, whereby one of them may compel the other to fulfil an obligation.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>56</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>System of accounting used to compile national accounts. Not to be confused with public service accounting.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5609</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for the conditions of actual use of the various official languages.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5612</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for a worker's personal protective equipment and for safety devices on machines and equipment.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5614</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for equipment subjected to a positive or negative pressure compared to atmospheric pressure.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5636</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for any product, instrument, equipment or system intended to compensate, reduce or neutralise the handicap, and also for measures taken to improve access and thus increase the independence of handicapped or aged persons in their daily life.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5640</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use also for EU bodies.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5643</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A financial instrument intended to reduce the gap in the economic performances of the Member States, thereby promoting economic and monetary union.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5655</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5656</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Intergovernmental group responsible for international monetary questions affecting the interests of developing countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5668</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Replaced on 1 January 2007 by the European Fisheries Fund (EFF).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5669</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The image which the general public has of an institution, person or service.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>568</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A system of agricultural production that avoids or minimises the use of chemicals.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5719</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>When referring to the animal variant, use “BSE”.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5726</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Do not confuse with "EU trade mark".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5734</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>For preference, use the generic term ‘veterinary medicinal product’.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5754</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The specification of the maximum acceptable limit for a pollutant with a safety margin to guarantee public safety.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5761</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Intergovernmental working groups supervised by the Council and responsible for matters concerning terrorism, internal security, police cooperation, organised crime and the free movement of persons. These groups no longer exist but prefigured the intergovernmental structure put in place by the Maastricht Treaty and the Schengen agreements.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5762</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for all entities which have the power of decision within an EU body.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5763</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for any body created under a European Union agreement and composed of representatives of the European Union and of one or more third countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5771</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The direct or indirect funding by persons or organisations of social, cultural, sporting or other activities or of their broadcasting.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5772</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with financial assistance provided under EU programmes and in accordance with EU policies.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5773</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Initiative aimed at improving stability and security in Europe by strengthening ties between NATO and the countries of Central and Eastern Europe or other States belonging to the CSCE.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5775</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5776</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5778</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5780</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5781</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN><HN>Central and Eastern European countries associated with the EU through association agreements. Eight countries joined the European Union in 2004 (Estonia, Hungary, Latvia, Lithuania, Poland, the Czech Republic, Slovakia and Slovenia) and two in 2007 (Bulgaria and Romania). In 2007, the list of CEEC countries comprises Albania, Bosnia-Herzegovina, Croatia, the former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia, Kosovo, Montenegro and Serbia.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5787</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Multi-annual forecast which for each major category of expenditure fixes maximum permitted ceilings for each budgetary year in question.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5805</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with “president of an institution”.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5815</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Replaced by the ordinary legislative procedure when the Lisbon Treaty came into force (1.12.2009).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5821</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for persons who treat patients by methods not recognised by conventional medicine.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5826</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for any campaign aimed at promoting the idea of European integration.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5830</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Occasion when a government, on its own initiative, defends its record before parliament.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5835</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for an appeal to an administrative court. Not to be confused with an appeal to an administrative authority.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5839</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Tax which allows pollution or noise to be emitted or which rewards services for waste treatment or which is levied on products which are likely to pollute.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>584</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for general studies, otherwise choose a more specific descriptor.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5848</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for geographical areas which are not confined within national frontiers.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5851</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for national and regional parliaments or assemblies.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5855</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for questions regarding the balanced division of powers between the EU, national and regional institutions.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5864</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The interconnection and interoperability of national transport, telecommunications and energy networks aimed at creating an area without internal frontiers.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5868</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>This comes from the application of a flat rate to the VAT base of each Member State.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>588</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Act of selling goods abroad at prices lower than those on the domestic market.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5887</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Do not confuse with "aviation security".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5891</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for campaigns launched to inform the general public. Combine with the field in question or with the name of the institution if the campaign refers to the image which the general public has of this institution.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5897</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use to describe the politics of one country, a group of countries or a region at a specific time.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5903</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for a show or any other public event where animals are used.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5928</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Civilian technology which contains possibilities for military use.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5930</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>This designation shall not be construed as recognition of a State of Palestine and is without prejudice to the individual positions of the EU Member States on this issues.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>594</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>With effect from the signing of the Lomé Convention in 1975, use "ACP countries".</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5940</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Work which is other than full-time and permanent, including part-time, evening and weekend work, fixed-term work, teleworking and outwork.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5941</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Work that, because of its nature or of factors peculiar to the industry in which it is performed, is available, at approximately the same time or times every year, for part or parts only of the year. This situation occurs particularly in agriculture and tourism.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5948</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Originated as informal consultation between the Member States in order to develop joint positions and jointly implement a European foreign policy. Enshrined in the Treaty on European Union, it was replaced by the common foreign and security policy. Use “CFSP”.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>595</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Association of several farmers for the purpose of working together or making joint investments.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5958</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Area protected by special measures to preserve a highly vulnerable natural habitat.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5975</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Unemployment due to variations in the business cycle.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5976</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The situation of a person who cannot be considered as unemployed since he is not looking for work. He is therefore no longer counted as part of the labour force.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5980</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Employment rate variations linked to the time of year.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>5981</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Unemployment resulting from changes in the structure of the economy, technical progress, re-siting of industries or changes in the composition of the work force.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6007</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Clause which authorises contracting parties to ignore certain provisions of an agreement if there is a threat to their essential interests.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6034</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Covers various types of territorial area. Not to be confused with the descriptor "local government".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6044</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Fuels not derived from oil.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6048</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>In 2008, as a consequence of the establishment of a single CMO (Common Market Organisation) regulation of the agricultural markets, the individual sector specific Management Committees were replaced by a single Management Committee for the Common Organisation of Agricultural Markets.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6050</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The "Comitology" Decision was repealed and replaced on 1 March 2011 by the "Comitology" Regulation.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6052</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with food supplement.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6056</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Refers to committees whose French title contains the expression 'comité paritaire'.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6061</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Set of economic policy measures aimed at correcting a country's major imbalances by providing it with structures, operating mechanisms and a price system close to those currently in force in the world market, all aimed, in the long term, at re-orientating production and investment decisions.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6064</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A methodical examination and review carried out to ascertain the general situation of a company or to assess whether a particular activity conforms with legal provisions or the rules of good management.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6081</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Incorporates those basic labour standards on which developed and developing countries agree. These standards apply to the right to organise trade unions, the right to collective bargaining, the banning of slavery and forced labour, non-discrimination and the minimum working age.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6091</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Generic term for the three European standardisation bodies (CEN, Cenelec and ETSI). Use with each specific body.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6103</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Waste which must be handled with particular care in view of the possible risks of injury to humans, animals or the environment.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6104</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Handing over to the appropriate institutions of several free copies of a literary or audiovisual work on or after their publication.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6105</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The practice of taking advantage of lower labour costs in certain countries (owing to lower social security and other contributions), thus attracting business away from other countries and thereby creating unfair competition.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6106</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Right awarded under a former law.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>611</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Strip of water between coastline and open sea having a maximum width of 12 miles.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6110</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The collection, organisation and distribution of all types of information on interactive magnetic and optical supports.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6112</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>When referring to the human variant, use “disease of the nervous system”.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6114</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Group of seven most industrialised countries (US, Japan, Canada, France, Germany, Italy and the UK). When Russia joined in 1998, it became the “Group of Eight”.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6116</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Permanent mechanism for consultation and concerted political action for the countries of Latin America and the Caribbean, resulting from the merger of the Contadora Group and the Lima Group in 1986.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6120</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>All the actions aimed at stimulating, disseminating and exploiting the results of research, technological development and demonstration (RTD) for the benefit and information of companies and other economic agents.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6125</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Progressive integration of the global economy.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6126</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Integration of sound, images (possibly animated) and text on a single support.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6128</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>With the entry into force of Regulation EU 2015/2424 amending the Community trade mark regulation on 23 March, OHIM became the European Union Intellectual Property Office (EUIPO), and the Community trade mark became the European Union trade mark.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6129</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Created in 1952 as the Customs Cooperation Council, the organisation was officially renamed the World Customs Organisation in 1994.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6130</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Dispute settlement system of the WTO which governments may resort to if they are of the conviction that certain rules or laws have not been respected.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6132</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Sexual desire directed towards children.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6134</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Comparative advertising means any advertising which explicitly or by implication identifies a competitor or goods or services offered by a competitor.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6140</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Only to be used for documents of a very general nature, otherwise choose a more specific descriptor.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6143</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Reform of the political structures in a country or group of countries, resulting in the transition from a planned economy to a market economy.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6146</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Agreement on Trade-Related Aspects of Intellectual Property Rights.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6148</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The Confederation of European Business adopted the name “BusinessEurope” in January 2007.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6151</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Geographical area covering those Member States who have adopted the euro as their currency.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6152</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Infectious disease of animals which can be transmitted to humans.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6160</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Use for the Eutelsat intergovernmental organisation, which was created in 1977 to manage a satellite telecommunications infrastructure in Europe. In July 2001, Eutelsat’s activities were transferred to a company under private law.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6163</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Created in 1924 as the International Office of Epizootics, the organisation was officially renamed the World Organisation for Animal Health in 2003.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6171</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The production, by way of vegetative reproduction, of a group of cells or organisms which are genetic duplicates and thus genetically identical to the original stock or ancestral cell.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6176</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The entire spectrum of worldwide, interactive data transmission and reception, including internet, interactive television and similar networked media.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6189</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Refers to the complete range of equipment, software and technical means used in and for storing and archiving data in numerical form.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6190</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The process of optical character recognition consists in the conversion, by means of a scanner or machine which recognises letters and characters through a mechanism of electronic conversion using a light source, of a numeric image into text, which can then subsequently be modified and processed by means of a word-processing programme.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6191</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Conversion of analog data or signals into digital data or signals.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6192</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Computer peripheral for digitising text and image.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>62</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Financial statement combining the accounts of two or more companies in a group.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6205</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6216</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Policy aimed at defending the specific interests of consumers by recognising their fundamental rights and by aiming to reduce inequalities, fight against disloyal practices, promote health and safety and improve the standard of living in general.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6219</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Replace the European Monitoring Centre on Racism and Xenophobia.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6222</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Comprises activities carried out under the first pillar (free movement of persons, asylum, immigration, visas, judicial cooperation in civil matters) and the third pillar (police and judicial cooperation in criminal matters).</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6223</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>On 4 February 2003 the State Union of Serbia and Montenegro superseded the Federal Republic of Yugoslavia, which had been proclaimed on 27 April 1992. On 3 June 2006 Montenegro declared independence and the Federal State split into two new independent States: the Republic of Serbia and the Republic of Montenegro.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6253</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The Social Policy Agreement has been incorporated into the EC Treaty by the Treaty of Amsterdam. The Social Policy Agreement sets out the EU's social policy objectives, whereby special emphasis has been put on equal opportunities and the fight against social exclusion.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6261</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A computer simulation of reality which uses 3D graphics to create a life-like environment.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6262</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The creation, editing or publishing of pictures by means of a computer.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6273</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Leave, other than annual leave, granted for family reasons, change of residence, training, etc.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6274</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Principle which allows Member States who so wish to make progress at a different pace or on different objectives outside the institutional framework of the European Union.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6275</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The linking of multimedia to web documents; the integration of text, images, sound, graphics, animation and video through hyperlinks.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6276</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Pages of computer text which are authored in software so as to allow extensive cross-referencing between related sections of text and associated graphic material.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6284</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use with name of relevant institution.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6288</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The office of High Representative of the Union for Foreign Affairs and Security Policy was instituted by the Lisbon Treaty (which came into force on 1.12.2009).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6292</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The way in which a society goes about producing goods and services, consisting of the forces and relations of production.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6298</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Rate of output which a worker is expected to maintain in order to receive a specific wage. Do not confuse with "labour standard".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6300</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The examination and evaluation of the possible consequences of the introduction of new technologies.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6305</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Academic or other investigative study undertaken in a natural setting, rather than in laboratories, classrooms, or other structured environments.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6309</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Model based on multifunctional, sustainable and competitive farming.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>631</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Special school for the training of future police and fire officers, etc.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6311</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Refers to the division and ownership of land.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6314</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The simultaneous growing of trees with food crops and/or livestock on the same piece of land.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6318</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The system of growing a sequence of different crops on the same ground so as to maintain or increase its fertility.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6319</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A container, often cylindrical in shape, for the storage of grain.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>632</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Study of relations with the environment, mainly physical or geographical.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6322</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The science concerned with the domestication and breeding of animals.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6325</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A procedure in which an independent third party awards a certificate attesting that a forest is being managed and used sustainably in accordance with agreed standards.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6327</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The objective of EFICS is to collect, coordinate, standardise, process and disseminate information concerning the forestry sector.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6333</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The ECU was a basket currency made up of the sum of fixed amounts of 12 of the 15 currencies of the EC Member States. The value of the ECU was calculated as a weighted average of the value of its component currencies. The ECU was replaced by the euro on a one-for-one basis on 1 January 1999.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6334</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Interbank interest rates calculated with the assistance of the European System Central Bank (ESCB).</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6335</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Rate of parity between the euro and national currencies joining the euro zone. Fixed and irrevocable since 01.01.1999.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>634</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The application of mathematical and statistical techniques to economic problems and theories.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6345</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Term used in a general sense to designate any vocational training undertaken by a worker throughout his working life.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6347</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>This strategy was introduced after the adoption of the Treaty of Amsterdam to create jobs and fight unemployment.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6350</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The relaxation of labour regulations, which are considered to be one of the main impediments to growth and job creation. Includes flexibility regarding wages, working hours, the organisation of work and also the use of manpower through flexible job and location practices.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6351</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Professional qualifications which no longer meet the demand or which are no longer valid, owing to technological change, for example. This situation can be remedied through vocational retraining.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6353</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Situation where the number of job-seekers is inferior to the demand.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6355</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The recruitment by various methods of employees from one company to another, often rival, company.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6356</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use to indicate a change of job within the same company as a result of redeployment or promotion.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6357</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The lowering in rank or position of a person, especially transferral to a poorer job.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6359</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A Member State which has not yet adopted the single currency, either intentionally or because it does not yet meet the conditions.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6360</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A Member State which has adopted the single currency.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6361</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The study of the mechanical properties of materials and the conditions under which they resist or deform when used.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6362</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A measurement technique designed to identify the most efficient practices. It provides a series of simple and transparent points of reference which, by means of tests, can help to monitor trends in competitiveness over a period of time, while at the same time offering a base from which to set targets and adopt the plans needed to attain them.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6363</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Weapons specifically designed to incapacitate combattants and equipment, while at the same time minimising the risk of death, permanent injury and irreversible damage to property and the environment.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6365</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Acts attributable to the State whereby a public authority entrusts to a third party û by means of a contractual act or a unilateral act with the prior consent of the third party û the total or partial management of services for which that authority would normally be responsible and for which the third party assumes the risk.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6366</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A contract which in terms of form, nature or type of signatory constitutes a commercial act.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6369</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Covers market and non-market services which the public authorities class as being of general interest and subject to specific public service obligations. Not to be confused with the descriptor "public service", which refers to the body providing a service.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6370</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Data in electronic form which are attached to or logically associated with other electronic data and which serve as a method of authentication.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6372</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Sanction imposed on a country as the result of a dispute between an international organisation and one or more countries, or between two or more international organisations.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6373</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>In 2008, the Union for the Mediterranean replaced the Euro-Mediterranean partnership formerly known as the "Barcelona Process". The partnership brings together the 27 Member States of the European Union and 16 partner countries from the South Mediterranean region and the Middle East.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6374</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Independent and objective examination of the pertinence, effectiveness, efficiency, impact and viability of a humanitarian intervention, in order to draw appropriate conclusions.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6377</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Refers to weapons and devices used against persons, not against equipment.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6383</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The science and technology of space flight.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6385</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The study of the influences exerted on living organisms by climate.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6386</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Branch of soil science concerned with the chemical composition, properties and reactions of soils.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6387</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The study of the relationship between geography and cultural.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6388</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The study of man's geographical distribution and spatial organisation.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6389</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The study of the characteristics of a region and their economic, ecological or social implications.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6390</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The branch of geology that is concerned with the structure, origin, and development of the topographical features of the earth's crust.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6391</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The branch of geology concerned with sedimentary rocks and deposits.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6394</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The branch of anthropology that deals with the scientific description of individual human societies.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6395</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Sociology applied to the world of work, e.g. the workplace as a social system, occupational status, racial and intergroup relations in the enterprise, etc.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>640</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Cooperation between the State and undertakings with a view to taking economic decisions jointly.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6400</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Policies and measures to reduce the emissions or enhance the sinks of greenhouse gases so as to mitigate the effects of climate change.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6407</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The acidification of water, soil and vegetation by the deposition of acidifying pollutants (sulphur dioxide, nitrogen oxides and ammonia).</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>641</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Reduction of production costs of a unit owing to an increase in its production capacity.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>648</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Study of transport requirements and the most appropriate ways in which to meet them.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>649</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>An economy in which the State intervenes but does not impose centralised planning.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6537</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A family into which one or both of the adult partners bring children from a previous relationship.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6540</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The dispersion of people originally belonging to one nation or having a common culture.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6544</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The process of renewal whereby losses in a population due to deaths are replaced by births.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6559</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Applies only to the sense of belonging to the European Union.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>656</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>All activities involved in the preparation of foodstuffs, comprising production, preserving, processing and distribution.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6570</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Nursing and medical care provided to terminally ill patients.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6609</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The practice of an organisation or group of like organisations voluntarily selecting, adopting and enforcing rules to produce compliance with a defined level of behaviour, without direct legislative interference by government.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>661</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Sector of the economy based on illicit working or illegal activities which do not appear in the national statistics.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6617</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The hearing and determination of a dispute, especially an industrial dispute, by an impartial referee selected or agreed upon by the parties concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6621</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The official annulment or rescindment (as of a law or sentence) from operation or effect.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6627</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not in the sense of theological debates.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>664</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>An ecological community considered together with the non-living factors of its environment as a unit.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>665</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Single European currency introduced in January 1999, the name of which was decided on at the Madrid European Council in December 1995. To be used instead of the generic term 'ecu' after 01.01.1999.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>666</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>All industrial activities involved in the processing of products of agricultural origin.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>668</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use specific terms.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6704</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be used in the context of the European Union.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6705</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Mechanisms which ensure that industries of different countries complement each other in an attempt to achieve economic integration.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6709</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Replaces the European security and defence policy  from the entry into force of the Treaty of Lisbon (1.12.2009).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>671</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Comparative study of educational theories and practices in various countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6711</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The European Consumer Centres Network (ECC-Net) was established in January 2005 after the merger of two existing consumer protection networks: the Network for the extra-judicial settlement of consumer disputes (EEJ-Net) and the Euroguichet Network.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6715</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The science of danger, which studies natural, technological or domestic risks and their prevention.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6716</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The branch of astronomy concerned with the evolution and structure of the universe.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6718</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Occasional or irregular work during peak periods or when other employees are absent.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>672</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The teaching of the elementary skills that pupils need to become productive citizens capable of civic engagement and sustaining competitive employment.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6725</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Use after 1 November 1993, date on which the Treaty of Maastricht came into force.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6727</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The objective of help for victims is to inform victims and their families of their rights, advise them on procedures to be taken and offer them psychological support at all stages of the legal process.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6739</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Boorish, often violent behaviour by noisy, rough groups of persons, sometimes causing damage to property in public places or at sporting events.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6743</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Intentional, needless damage and destruction, especially of public buildings and places.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6744</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The study of methods of improving the quality of the human race, especially by selective breeding.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6745</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The working poor are households with an income below the poverty line.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6754</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A manufacturing or service business set up specifically to facilitate the reintegration of unemployed people through the exercise of an economic activity.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6756</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Enterprise with fewer than 10 employees.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>676</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Activities or programmes organised outside of the school system but directed towards precise educational objectives.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6775</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>To be used only for indexing documents which refer to the creation, development and maintenance of websites.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6781</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The minimum food, clothing and housing needs of a human being.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6782</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The position of the regions and their influence on the various European policies.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6785</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The transfer of income and public service provision to individuals and social groups without payment so that they can enjoy an improved standard of living.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6786</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The economic and measurable character of a good or service, taking into account its cost and offer and demand.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6789</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Not to be confused with food additive.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>68</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use only for local administrations. Not to be confused with the descriptors "regional and local authorities" and "local authority".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>680</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Instructing the general public in the basic principles of health and hygiene.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>682</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Form of education for pupils with special needs, such as the mentally or physically handicapped.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6851</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The application of telematics in transport.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6852</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for indexing global satellite systems used for navigation and positioning.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6855</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>This covers all services connected with an aircraft, such as refuelling and maintenance, and passenger, baggage and cargo handling.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6883</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Government by a small group of people.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6886</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A party which extols national pride, sometimes possessing xenophobic or isolationist tendencies.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6892</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use to index documents concerning the linguistic and legislative qualities of a law.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6897</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Governance refers to the process whereby elements in society wield power and authority, and influence and enact policies and decisions concerning public life.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6901</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for the sale of products from machines. For "automatic teller machine", use the descriptor "electronic banking".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6902</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Money used for the initial investment in a project or startup company, for proof-of-concept, market research, or initial product development.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6905</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Students and trainees who, for reasons of inaptitude, financial problems, etc., do not complete an organised period of training.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6909</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The adaptation of scientific and technical knowledge to make it accessible to non-specialists.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6910</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Knowledge management involves the identification and analysis of available and required knowledge assets and knowledge asset related processes, and the subsequent planning and control of actions to develop both the assets and the processes so as to fulfil organisational objectives.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>6913</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Outsourcing is when a company purchases a product or process from an outside supplier rather than producing in house.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>695</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use specific terms.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7134</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for the economies of countries which abandoned the communist system in 1989 in order to adopt an alternative system.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7136</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A defined minimum service of a specified quality available to all users and consumers in the Union and, taking into account specific national conditions, at an affordable price. Not to be confused with "services of general interest" or "public service".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7137</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The International Criminal Tribunal is empowered to prosecute persons responsible for serious violations of international humanitarian law on a defined territory (e.g. the “International Criminal Tribunal for the former Yugoslavia”, the “International Criminal Tribunal for Rwanda”). Not to be confused with the “International Criminal Court” or the “International Court of Justice”.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7138</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Philosophical and historical perspective of a united Europe.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7185</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Free-trade agreement set up in 1992 by three central European countries (Czechoslovakia, Poland and Hungary) and bringing together EU partner countries and countries seeking EU membership. At 1 January 2007, the members of CEFTA were Croatia, the Former Yugoslav Republic of Macedonia, Serbia, Montenegro, Albania, Bosnia and Herzegovina, Moldova and Kosovo.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7189</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>This term originated in the 1980s when the socialist French President, Franþois Mitterrand, was forced to adopt a power-sharing solution when a government of the right was elected. The term is now also used to describe similar situations in other countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7193</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>An independent, permanent court which tries persons accused of the most serious crimes of international concern, namely genocide, crimes against humanity and war crimes. Not to be confused with the International Criminal Tribunal (for Rwanda and the former Yugoslavia) and the International Court of Justice of the United Nations, which deals primarily with disputes between States.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7194</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Term used with regard to the area of freedom, security and justice (AFSJ).</SN><HN>As of the entry into force of the Lisbon Treaty (01.12.2009), use "decision (EU)".</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7198</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A State in Oceania comprising more than 600 islands in the archipelago of the Caroline Islands, with four constituent States: Chuuk, Kosrae, Pohnpei (Ponape) and Yap.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7207</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7212</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for the drafting of administrative documents.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7221</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>End of mandate: 31.12.2008.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>73</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Introduced in the 1970s, the medium-term financial assistance (MTFA) and Community loan mechanisms provided mutual financial support for Member States facing serious balance-of-payments difficulties. In 1988, they were merged into the balance-of-payments facility. From 2002, this financial assistance has been for Member States that have not adopted the euro.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>731</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Principle by which certain types of occupation are specially designated for the handicapped and must be reserved for them.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7353</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Territory or territorial unit administratively attached to an authority or state with which it is not contiguous.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7365</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The breaking of a binding administrative regulation, normally incurring an administrative penalty.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>737</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Aid from the viewpoint of the donor country.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7375</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Independent political force of the right or left which forms coalitions with the right or left.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7378</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>In a regional context; not to be confused with "autonomist party".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7382</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Benefit awarded to needy persons who do not possess sufficient funds to maintain themselves and who have either never paid social security contributions or have not paid them for long enough to receive the benefits normally due to a wage-earner.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7396</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A health care directive that tells others how a person would like to be treated if they lose their capacity to make decisions about health care. The term living will is often used when a person is planning for their last illness, but a health care directive can be made in any circumstances.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>743</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Energy produced by the movement of waves.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>744</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Energy which is non-pollutant, whether renewable or not.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>781</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Method of teaching involving computers.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7813</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Agreement signed on 23 June 2000, for a period of 20 years with a clause providing for a review every five years, between the 15 EU member States and 76 African, Caribbean and Pacific (ACP) countries. This Agreement succeeds takes the place of the Lomé Agreements, which had governed relations between the EU and the ACP countries since 1975.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7926</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Totality of the intellectual resources and skills available for a business activity.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7929</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Investigation by a court of the legality of decisions taken by a subordinate body.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7934</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Cooperation between public authorities and private businesses for the purpose of carrying out infrastructure projects or providing public utilities.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7939</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Disparities between individuals, households, businesses and geographical areas at various socioeconomic levels with regard to access to information technology and use of the Internet for a wide range of activities.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7941</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Administrative or legislative measures adopted to regulate or promote the use of one or more languages.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7942</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Voluntary efforts by businesses to incorporate social and environmental concerns into their corporate activities and their relations with interested parties.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7947</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Unsolicited messages sent by electronic means for the purpose of direct marketing.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7948</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>System of beliefs and values common to the members of a given organisation that guides their behaviour.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7949</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Measures taken by an employer to help employees threatened with redundancy to find new jobs in other companies.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7951</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Economy based on knowledge and technological innovation leading to the creation of a network of expertise.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7952</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Conference comprising the presidents or chairmen of the parliamentary groups.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>7955</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Undifferentiated cell from an embryo, a foetus or adult tissues that is capable of dividing, differentiating into other cell types and multiplying in culture.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>812</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Place where imported goods or goods for export can be stored or processed without payment of customs duties.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>82</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Physical, social and managerial factors affecting a worker's job.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8278</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8279</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Created on 01/01/2007, the region comprises the former counties of Copenhagen and Frederiksborg, the municipalities of Copenhagen and Frederiksberg, and the municipal regional municipality of Bornholm.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8280</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Created on 01/01/2007, the region comprises the former counties of Ringkjøbing and Århus, plus part of the counties of Viborg and Vejle.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8281</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Created on 01/01/2007, the region comprises the former county of Nordjylland (North Jutland), plus part of the county of Viborg.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8282</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Created on 01/01/2007, the region comprises the former counties of Roskilde, Storstrøm and Vestsjælland.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8283</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Created on 01/01/2007, the region comprises the former counties of Fyns, Ribe and Sønderjylland (South Jutland), plus part of the county of Vejle.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8365</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8366</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8367</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8369</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8386</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Regional commission of the United Nations Economic and Social Council (Ecosoc), which initiates measures to promote regional economic development and to strengthen economic relations between countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8393</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Joint and Co-sponsored United Nations Programme on HIV and AIDS (JCP/UNAIDS).</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8396</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Political forum for regional and intergovernmental cooperation between 11 countries in the Baltic Sea region (Denmark, Estonia, Finland, Germany, Iceland, Latvia, Lithuania, Norway, Poland, Russia, Sweden) and the European Commission.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8400</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Preferential trade area for the countries of East Africa and Southern Africa.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8404</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The ITUC was created on 1 November 2006, superseding the International Confederation of Free Trade Unions (ICFTU) and the World Confederation of Labour (WCL).</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8407</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>After the reform of the Staff Regulations of Officials of the European Communities in May 2004, the old “B”, “C” and “D” categories were replaced by the assistants’ function group “AST”.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8411</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Principle of international law which means that two or more countries agree to cooperate in a specific field.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8419</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The values, traditions, attitudes and strategies associated with the way in which politics is conducted.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8427</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Europeanisation of the civil law of the EU Member States.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8428</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>All non-profit movements and associations which are independent of the State and whose objective is to transform, through concerted effort, the social policies, standards and structures at national and international level.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8430</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Process of incorporating the political and economic dynamics of the EU into the drafting of national policy.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8438</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Science of determining the shape, size and field of gravity of the earth.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8442</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Set of ideas based on the concept of a nation and the identification of individuals or communities with those ideas.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8458</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use with “lay magistrate” (challenge to a juror), “evidence” (challenge to a witness) or “judge” (challenge to a judge).</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8459</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Payment of European subsidies tied to the farm and not to production.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8465</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use with the institution, body or agency concerned.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8466</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Action taken by a public authority to bring about social change in the medium and long term. It is based on certain values and objectives and is implemented using a variety of methods. It applies on the territory within which the authority is authorised to act.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8471</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Form of tourism practised in areas of natural interest which are little affected by man in order to encourage an appreciation of biodiversity and cultural events, respect for the environment and the protection of flora and fauna.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8472</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Form of tourism which promotes the protection and enhancement of the natural, cultural and human environment. It draws on concepts of sustainable development and is of socioeconomic benefit to local and regional communities.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8474</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>With the entry into force of the Treaty of Lisbon (1.12.2009), common strategies in the area of freedom, security and justice and the common foreign and security policy have been replaced by decisions of the Council. Use "(EU) decision".</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8479</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Institutional method which makes use of the mechanisms of the first pillar of the EU, in contrast to the intergovernmental method (i.e. intergovernmental cooperation), which is used for the other pillars.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8481</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Police force established under the European Security and Defence Policy which takes part in international civilian crisis management operations and in conflict prevention.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8488</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Created in 2001 from the merger of the International Union for Inland Navigation (IUIN) and the Rhine International Navigation Consortium.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8542</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>After the reform of the Staff Regulations of Officials of the European Communities in May 2004, the old “A” and “LA” categories were replaced by the administrators’ function group “AD”.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8549</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The EGF aims to help workers made redundant as a result of changing global trade patterns to find another job as quickly as possible.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>855</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The study of the relationship between workers and their environment, especially the equipment they use.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>8553</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The Lisbon Treaty, which came into force on 1 December 2009, amalgamates the European Union and the European Community into a single European Union. The terms "European Union" and "EU" replace "European Community", "Community" and "EC".</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>858</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Operation in which a negotiable instrument is purchased at a discount on its face value representing interest on the amount up to the maturity date.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>874</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Private body whose activities are recognised as being in the public interest.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>880</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>International monetary system, elaborating on the pure gold standard, in which gold is an international currency alongside one or more key currencies, convertibility into gold being limited to key currencies.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>882</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>International monetary system in which each unit of currency is worth a fixed amount of gold.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>887</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Society in which welfare and social security are provided by the State through its departments and agencies.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>892</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The branch of anthropology that deals with races and peoples, their relations to one another, their origins and their distinctive characteristics.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>901</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>National currency held by foreign companies or banks and traded on the international money market.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>902</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Dollars which are held by banks or companies outside the United States and traded on the international money market.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>908</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Informal association of the Ministers of Defence of European NATO countries. It was dissolved in 1994.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>916</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>The enrichment of fresh or salt water by nutrients, causing an accelerated growth of algae and other plants which leads to a deterioration in the water quality.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>924</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Reduction or minimisation of tax liability by lawful means.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>934</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Emigration of qualified persons to a country or region which offers them better working conditions.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>962</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Relationship between the landowner and the farmer who works the land.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>963</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Cultivation of an agricultural area by the landowner himself.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>964</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Intermediate stage between owner farming and tenant farming.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>969</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Aid provided by churches, foundations, etc.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>97</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Entry for a limited period, with suspension of customs duties, of goods intended for re-export.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>972</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use this and specific terms for wild animals, either at liberty or in captivity.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>978</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use only in cases where EAGGF is understood in a general sense without distinguishing between Guidance and Guarantee Sections.</SN><HN>Replaced, since 1 January 2007, by the European Agricultural Fund for Rural Development (EAFRD) and European Agricultural Guarantee Fund (EAGF).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>979</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>On 1 January 2007, this fund was replaced by the European Agricultural Guarantee Fund (EAGF).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>980</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>On 1 January 2007, this fund was replaced by the European Agricultural Fund for Rural Development (EAFRD).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>982</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Arrangement under which a landowner lets land to a farmer in return for an annual payment not dependent on the yield from the farm.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>998</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A company controlled directly or indirectly by another company, known as the parent or holding company.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>999</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>A company set up jointly by two or more parent companies which themselves remain legally and financially independent.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_047e5912</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The EBA was established on 1 January 2011 as part of the European System of Financial Supervision (ESFS) and took over all existing responsibilities and tasks of the Committee of European Banking Supervisors.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_062f6587</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Entered in force on 27 September 2012. The ESM has taken over the tasks fulfilled by the European Financial Stability Facility (EFSF) and the European Financial Stabilisation Mechanism (EFSM).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_2d0e694e</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>The Economic and Financial Committee was preceded by the Monetary Committee.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_4e3beee2</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Replaced the ‘European Fisheries Fund’ (EFF) established for the period 2007-2013.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_777eba81</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Entered into force on 1 January 2013.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_964c9649</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for documents which deal with all of these countries.</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_a02d5941</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Established in 1999 to discuss key issues for global economic stability.</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_b605a1d4</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><HN>Established by the General Assembly resolution 60/251 of 15 March 2006 as one of its subsidiary bodies, in replacement of the ‘Commission on Human Rights’. Source: United Nations Human Rights Council. Available at: http://www.ohchr.org/en/hrbodies/hrc/pages/hrcindex.aspx (Accessed: 25 January 2016).</HN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_c8c80a5b</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Do not confuse with "air safety".</SN></RECORD><RECORD><DESCRIPTEUR_ID>c_dcc650ef</DESCRIPTEUR_ID><SN>Use for investment funds (non-harmonised funds) not regulated by the UCITS directive. Source: EUR-Lex, Directive 2011/61/EU on Alternative Investment Fund Managers, (32011L0061).</SN></RECORD></SCOPE_NOTE>